James M. Hale IT INFRASTRUCTURE ENGINEER

2630 Adams Mill Rd NW, Apt 207 Washington, D.C. 20009

413-896-7607 jmhale08@gmail.com jmhale@protonmail.com

Profile

Senior-level engineer with over eight years of experience. Specializing in architecting and deploying secure and scalable systems with high availability, using cloud-based and on-premises infrastructure resources, including hybrid solutions.

DevOps and security-focused. Experienced in Agile methodologies, including Scrum and Kanban.

Specialties include: AWS, VMware, networking, automation and security.

Education and Certifications

University of Massachusetts Amherst - B.S. Computer Science, 2009

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate - License AWS-ASA-10580

Relevant Skills

Languages:	Python, Go, Ruby, Groovy, PHP, Perl, YAML, JSON
Configuration Management:	Puppet, Chef, SaltStack, Ansible.
IaaS Platforms:	AWS, VMware, Google Compute Engine, OpenStack
InfoSec tools:	Nmap, Kali Linux, Metasploit, Snort, Nessus
Container technologies:	Docker, Kubernetes, Mesos, AWS ECS

- Primarily focused on deploying fault-tolerant, highly-available, and secure systems across a multitude of platforms
- Expertise with cloud and on-premises infrastructure platforms, IaaS/PaaS, including designing and implementing hybrid solutions.
- Security-minded. Aim to identify, assess and remediate risk and vulnerabilities in platforms.
- Strive to provide infrastructure as a service to software developers and facilitate their deployment tasks.
- Experience with automating deployment and administration tasks with configuration management platforms.
- Knowledge of Datacenter and NOC operations.

Work Experience

Blackboard, LLC, Washington, D.C.

Senior DevOps Engineer, November 2016 – Present

- Research, design, develop, document and implement solutions for fault tolerance, performance, capacity, and configuration management for various data center operations.
- Design, develop and implement documentation or tools to facilitate Technical Support team responsibilities.
- Identify and drive opportunities to improve automation for deployment, management, and tooling, using Python, Ruby and Groovy, among other languages.
- Support and improve a highly available and fault tolerant SaaS offering.
- Identify platform vulnerabilities and help design and engineer security solutions.

The Washington Post, Washington, D.C.

Senior Infrastructure Engineer, January 2015 – November 2016

- Implement ephemeral, long-lived and immutable infrastructure as code, using AWS CloudFormation and internally-built solutions
- Maintain infrastructure resources in an auditable and repeatable fashion using configuration management platforms and version control systems
- Responsible for designing and implementing robust network and security architectures
- Help to maintain a strong information security posture for data in transit and data at rest
- Provide expertise to software developers on AWS services and best practices, such as EC2 (incl. EBS, ASG, ELB), VPC/Direct Connect, Route53, S3, IAM/KMS, RDS, SNS, SQS, SES, and CloudWatch
- Contribute to internal software projects, centered around the orchestration of infrastructure resources and the continuous deployment of containerized applications to test and production environments

Unix Systems Engineer, December 2011 – January 2015

- Managed physical and cloud-based infrastructure for the print, mobile, and web properties of Washington Post Media
- Supported content management systems and applications utilizing Apache, Nginx, Tomcat, and dynamic Java applications deployed on Glassfish or WebLogic application servers.
- Maintained Unix production, stage, and test environments, utilizing RedHat 5/6/7, CentOS 5/6/7, Solaris 9 & 10, AIX 5.3, HP-UX and Mac OS X Server
- Performed code deployments for development teams
- Carried out system maintenance and upgrades as needed, including backups and restorations
- Participated in 24x7 on-call rotation
- Assisted with a major data center relocation

Client Systems Engineer, September 2010 – December 2011

- Developed and maintained Windows and Mac desktop images, software deployments, and application patching while also identifying and resolving desktop security issues.
- Provided technical expertise to assist with implementation of desktop technologies: Windows and Mac
 desktops and laptops and their operating systems, desktop applications, management systems, and
 tools
- Created and supported desktop management related technical policies and procedures; helped to create and maintain related documentation.
- Administered and assisted in deploying LANDesk 8.8 & 9 environments and Symantec Endpoint Protection for a client base of 3000+ machines.

- Deployed regularly scheduled and out of band security/OS patches and updates via LANDesk and other mechanisms.
- Co-developed an asset management system to track physical assets via barcode scanning devices.

System Support Analyst, July 2009 – September 2010

- Actively monitored an extensive production environment for washingtonpost.com and other high-traffic Post properties
- Acted as a liaison between coworkers and the development and infrastructure technology teams
- Provisioned, integrated, diagnosed, and maintained PC and Macintosh clients in an Active Directory environment